<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on My blog</title>
    <link>https://zecakpm.github.io/portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zecakpm.github.io/portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB - Creating, querying and transforming data with Python</title>
      <link>https://zecakpm.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zecakpm.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>Image Credits Smith Collection / Gado / Getty Images
MongoDB MongoDB is a highly scalable database. All info is stored as JSON files, which makes it very fast and scalable.
Terminology  Collection - name used for tables  Objective I will be exploring how to create, query, and transform data into a Pandas DataFrame in Python.
With no further delays, let&amp;rsquo;s get our hands dirty.
Importing libraries and establish a connection with Mongo Server from flask_pymongo import pymongo as pm from pymongo import MongoClient as mc #Establish connection connection = mc(&amp;#39;localhost&amp;#39;,27017) Creating a database If a database does not exist under this name, a new database will be created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short period classification of The New York Stock Exchange, Nasdaq Stock Market &amp; London Stock Exchange companies</title>
      <link>https://zecakpm.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zecakpm.github.io/portfolio/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>STOCK MARKET Stock market prediction is a challenge for investors and advisers. The analysis of time series using APIs + classification models allow investors to use a wide range of information that could lead to better asset allocation.
Model To reduce risk exposure we propose a short period classification using the Random Forest model.
Structure Choose Markets &amp;amp; Companies Selected major companies from NYSE, Nasdaq, and LSE.
Collect data Used yahoo API to gather company data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
